Adriana Carla Maziero Camarotto

Front End Web Developer www.linkedin.com/in/adriana-camarotto

Mobile Number: 07738771515

Email: adriana.camarotto@gmail.com

I am currently studying a bootcamp Front End Web Developer. I had achieved a University Degree in Business and Management (2013). Co-founder (2013) of the extinct Tricam Embedded Systems company, where I was responsible for the administrative and financial areas. I attended the workshop EMPRETEC in 2015 (the United Nations - UNCTAD entrepreneurial education program). I'm also a mentor of the Technovation Challenge, a worldwide entrepreneurship and technology challenge that encourages girls to develop mobile apps that solve a social problem through programming and entrepreneurship. I have been mentoring several teams (junior and senior) since 2016, including mentoring the South American Champion team in 2018 of the challenge. I have a passion for entrepreneurship and technology. I have a Residence Card, and EU Scheme Pre-settlement and I can work and Leave to remain in the UK.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- HTML;
- CSS;
- Git;
- GitHub;
- JavaScript;
- Bootstrap;
- VScode;

- Business Model Canvas;
- Business plan;
- Strategic planning;
- Design Thinking;
- Microsoft Office;
- Video editing;

CERTIFICATIONS

- EMPRETEC (UNCTAD);
- Strategic Planning (UNOESC);
- PEIEX (UNOESC);
- Design Thinking (UNOESC),
- Pre-Incubated Business Training (NIT / UNOESC);
- Startup Weekend 2018 (UNOESC);
- HTML5 + Bootstrap Front End Programming Workshop for Beginners 2019 (UNOESC).
- 5DCC Five Days Coding Challenge 2022 (Code Institute),
- Discover's Path Conectar 2022 (Rocketseat).

LANGUAGES SKILLS

Portuguese – native English – second language

EDUCATION

2022 - 2023 - edX / Skills for life UK - Gov.Uk

BOOTCAMP FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

2011 – 20013 - UNOESC - Joaçaba – Brazil - www.unoesc.edu.br

GRADUATION IN TECHNOLOGIST IN BUSINESS AND MANAGEMENT

According to the educational institution, the technology course in management processes focuses on the job market focused on practical activities that instigate a business vision, with emphasis on organisational processes and business. The student is prepared to develop and implement administrative strategies, gain market insight, formulate business plans for new ventures and existing organisations, and be able to make decisions that improve levels of business competitiveness.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

03/2022 - present - Tesco Pharmacy - Wells, UK - www.tesco.com

MEDICINE COUNTER ASSISTANT As a medicine counter assistant (starter) in a Pharmacy I am someone who is a team player learning technical skills with a strong customer focus to accurately dispense medication for our customers according to the Standard Operating Procedures. I am responsible for advising on the range of Pharmacy services available and take time to understand the customer's needs, explaining the benefits of the products in a way they understand. I respond to customer queries in relation to prescription medicines, informing the Pharmacist of any complaints. I offer information to customers, on common ailments, symptoms, only selling products that are right for them in a confident, friendly and professional manner, providing to our customers with a great service, and ensuring we trade safely and legally to make them want to visit our Pharmacy again.

As a trainee I am responsible for completing corporate and departmental training and Keeping up to date with legal and professional developments in pharmacy.

11/2020 – 03/2022 – Tesco – Ltd – Shepton Mallet, UK – www.tesco.com

As CUSTOMER ASSISTANT I used to work in the ready meal department, where the best before dates are really sensitive, so I pay double attention to the dates and products rotation to assure the best for the customers. I am building good relationships with colleagues in a great team spirit. As part of this great team, I am focused on delivering all my department routines following company policies and adhering to health and safety guidelines, to assure that customers leave the store having experienced a great shopping experience.

10/2019 – 03/2020 Skills Direct Ltd – Shepton Mallet, UK – www.skillsdirectltd.com

As **OPERATOR MACHINE** – as a temporary employee I perform necessary pre-operation activities to ensure proper equipment start up and operation on multiple pieces of equipment. Test operation of machines periodically. Housekeeping and sanitation. As MANUFACTURING OPERATIVE/PACKERS as a temporary employee I work in a busy production environment. The role consists of the following: Working on packings lines and following client specific packing designs; Loading food materials, adhering to site food safety and health and safety at all times, Palletising, wrapping and labelling products; Quality Control checks; Weighing and counting ingredients.

12/2013 – 05/2019 - Tricam Sistemas Embarcados - Luzerna – Brazil

ADMINISTRATIVE MANAGER – As an Administrative in a family business, I did everything from sales; admissions and layoffs; cash flow management; stock control; strategic and marketing planning; internal process management, and everything in between. One of the achievements was the development and sale of a modular product to one of the major customers with a view to the international market, resulting in increased system sales, reduced time and cost of product maintenance for the customer, reduced warranty costs and maximise user experience for this customer's products.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

2016 – 2020 – TECHNOVATION CHALLENGE - https://technovationchallenge.org/

MENTOR - As a volunteer mentor to the Technovation Challenge, encourage girls to learn how to program to develop mobile apps that solve social problems in their communities and around the world. I teach them sustainable business models and business plans for their startups. In 2018 the GirlsUp team, mentored by me, was a South American champion in the Technovation Challenge Junior category, with Life4down App, and in 2019 this same team was a senior semi-finalist in the Technovation Challenge.

08/2017 - 06/2019 - SEBRAE SC

MEMBER OF LIDER PROGRAM - Member of the Lider Program team, promoted by the SEBRAE / SC initiative in partnership with the 12 cities that make up the Midwest Santa Catarina Municipalities Association (AMOOC), which aims to promote the mobilisation, qualification and integration of regional leaders for the elaboration of a regional development agenda.

Link: https://www.ammoc.org.br/noticias/index/ver/codMapaItem/42458/codNoticia/466539

03/2016 - 12/2018 - ACIOC - Associação Comercial e Industrial do Oeste Catarinense -

MEMBER - Within the **ACIOC-NJE** (Young Entrepreneur Nucleus), I was the coordinator of the first edition of the Young Entrepreneur Nucleus Award. Developed several activities such as drafting the NJE Award participation notice, marketing planning, strategic planning, event organisation and social actions, among others. I participated in training focused on entrepreneurship.

Link: http://www.acioc.com.br/premio-nje

08/2015 - 08/2017 - ITL - Incubadora Tecnologica Luzerna - http://www.incubadoraluzerna.com.br

CHAIRMAN OF THE ADVISORY BOARD INCUBATED COMPANIES - I was responsible for presiding monthly, in ordinary and extraordinary sections; Ensure compliance with the institution's internal regulations, suggest plans and programs, standards, criteria and other instruments; Propose Goals Plan and Board of Directors and forms of performance appraisal of incubated companies and projects, in view of the reports presented and analyses made by the Board, using a standardised methodology; Request and propose to the director routine operational demands.